Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- IV. Printed Material, 1750-1950 (Box 77-81, Box S/67-S/69)
  - A. Libretti and Synopses (Box 77-78)
    - Paisiello, Giovanni
      - Il duello [comico]. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; xx, 36 p., Language note: Italian.; Libretto by Giambattista Lorenzi. (Box-folder 78/6)
      - La finta amante., Photoreproduction of typed copy; 40 p.; Language note: Italian.; Libretto by Giambattista Lorenzi. (Box-folder 78/7)
      - Nina, o sia la pazza per amore. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; 48 p., Language note: Italian.; Libretto by Giambattista Lorenzi.; Signed by Serge Lifar on first recto page. (Box-folder 78/8)
    - Schreker, Franz
      - Spanisches Fest [Der Geburtstag der Infantin.] Wien: Universal Edition, 1926; 8 p., Language note: German.; Published synopsis (“Frei nach Oskar Wildes Novelle ‘Der Geburtstag der Infantin’”). (Box-folder 78/9)
    - Whitworth, Geoffrey
      - Le jardin enchanté., Typed synopsis; 6 p.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 78/10)
    - [Unidentified composer/librettist.]
      - Rats, Autograph synopsis, in ink; 3 p. (one bifolio on music manuscript paper), “d’après la fable de La Fontaine ‘Le rat de village et le rat de campagne’.”; Language note: French. (Box-folder 78/11)
  - B. Books, Monographs, Programs, etc. (Box 79-80, Box S/67, Box S/68, Box S/69)
    - D’Armana, Jean
      - Le crépuscule des dieux. Bordeaux: Delmas, 1936., Libretto; 61 p.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 79/1)
    - Checchi, Eugenio
      - Rossini. Firenze: G. Barbèra, 1898; 6, 200 p., Language note: Italian. (Box-folder S/67)
    - Croce, Benedetto
      - Saggi sulla letteratura italiana del seicento. Bari: Giuseppe Laterza & Figli, 1911; 23, 444 p., Language note: Italian. (Box-folder S/68)
    - De Guarinoni, Eugenio
      - Indice generale: Archivio musicale Noseda. [Milan]: [s.n.], n.d.; [2], 420 p., Language note: Italian.; Lacking pages 1-12 (in foreword; includes page numbers 13, 14 only); 1-12 (in main text). (Box-folder 79/2)
    - Finck, Henry T.
      - Léon Bakst and Serge de Diaghileff’s Ballet Russe., Monograph extracted from the New York Evening Post, 1915 Nov 20; 5 p.; Language note: English. (Box-folder 79/3)
    - Gastoué, Amédée
      - Les primitifs de la musique française. Paris: Henri Laurens, 1922; 117 p., Language note: French. (Box-folder 80/1)
    - Gozzi, Carlo
      - Théâtre fiabesque. Paris: Michel Lévy Frères, 1865; 357 p., Translated by Alphonse Royer.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 80/2)
    - [Jullien, Adolphe]
      - Bibliothèque musicale de M. Adolphe Jullien. Vente du 23 juin 1933. Paris, Hôtel Drouot. Salle No. 9., [No publication data], 52 p.; Language note: French. (Box-folder 80/3)
    - Parente, Alfredo
      - Colori e forme nella musica: Il probleme dell'interferenza delle arti e l'estetica del futurismo. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; 20 p., Language note: Italian.; Monograph extracted from La Rassegna musicale (Torino), no. 1, January 1930. (Box-folder 80/4)
      - Critica e storiografia musicale: Premesse metodologiche. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; 27 p., Language note: Italian.; Monograph extracted from La Rassegna musicale (Torino), no. 5, September 1930. (Box-folder 80/5)
      - Natura estetica dell'armonia. Firenze: Felice Le Monnier, 1936; 8 p., Language note: Italian.; Monograph extracted from La Rassegna musicale (Torino), no. 11, 1936 (p. 326-333).; Laid in: Parente's business card. (Box-folder 80/6)
      - Note sull'estetica musicale contemporanea in Italia. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d.; 26 p., Language note: Italian.; Monograph extracted from La Rassegna musicale (Torino), no. 3, May 1931. (Box-folder 80/7)
      - Pensieri di F. de Sanctis intorno alla musica. Napoli: Edizioni "Aspetti Letterari", 1934; 20 p., Language note: Italian.; Monograph extracted from La Rassegna musicale (Torino), no. 1, May-June 1934. (Box-folder 80/8)
    - Pirro, André
      - Les clavecinistes. Paris: Henri Laurens, n.d.; 125 p., Language note: French. (Box-folder 80/9)
    - Scherillo, Michele
      - L'opera buffa napoletano durante il settecento. [S.l.]: Remo Sandron, n.d.; 11, 55 p., Language note: Italian. (Box-folder S/69)
  - C. Serials (Box 80)
    - L’Arte. (Italian, French) Milano: September-December 1956 (vol. 20); 128 p. (Box-folder 80/10)
    - Innen-Dekoration. (German) Darmstadt: January 1929 (vol. 40); 8 p. (Box-folder 80/11)
    - Das Theater. (German) Berlin: December 1925 (vol. 6, no. 23); 20 p. (Box-folder 80/12)
    - Das Theater. (German) Berlin: November 1926 (vol. 7, no. 21); 13 p. (Box-folder 80/13)
    - Das Theater (German): hand-colored illustration, ca. 1920; 1 p. (Box-folder 80/14)
  - D. Photographs (Box 81)
    - Cecchetti, Enrico, Inscribed to “Mis [sic] Leonora Sher”; dated 1916.; Photographer: Count Jean de Stre[lec]ki (partially illegible). (Box-folder 81/1)
    - Cecchetti, Enrico, In Pétroushka. Includes typed synopsis of the ballet.; Undated [ca. 1911]. (Box-folder 81/2)
    - Duncan, Isadora, Undated. (Box-folder 81/3)
    - Fokina, Vera, Inscribed to “Miss Shier.”; Undated. (Box-folder 81/4)
    - Fokina, Vera, Reproduction of a photograph previously signed by Fokina.; Undated. (Box-folder 81/5)
    - Fokine, Michel, Undated. (Box-folder 81/6)
    - Galli, Rosina, Undated [ca. 1914-16].; Photographer: C. Mishkin (New York). (Box-folder 81/7)
    - Hoffman, Gertrude, Inscribed, on both recto and verso, to “Senora [sic] Shier.”; Undated.; Photographer: Frank Bangs. (Box-folder 81/8)
    - Karsavina, Thamar, In Schéhérazade.; Undated [ca. 1910]. (Box-folder 81/9)
    - Lind, Jenny, Photograph of a painting of Lind attributed to S.F.B. Morse.; Undated. (Box-folder 81/10)
    - Lopokova, Lydia [two copies], Undated; second copy of photograph is dated 1917 on verso.; Photographer: Burke Atwell. (Box-folder 81/11)
    - Marmein, Miriam, Inscribed to Leonora Shier.; Dated 1947 on verso.; Photographer: DeBellis (New York). (Box-folder 81/12)
    - Nijinsky, Vaclav, In Pétrouchka.; Undated [ca. 1911].; Photographer: Mishkin (New York). (Box-folder 81/13)
    - Nijinsky, Vaclav, In Le Spectre de la Rose.; Undated [ca. 1911].; Photographer: Mishkin (New York). (Box-folder 81/14)
    - Nijinsky, Vaclav, Undated. (Box-folder 81/15)
    - Pauley, Andreas, In Bacchanale.; Undated.; Photographer: Moffett. (Box-folder 81/16)
    - Pauley, Andreas, Dated 1919.; Photographer: Moffett (Chicago). (Box-folder 81/17)
    - Pavlova, Anna, Undated. (Box-folder 81/18)
    - Revalles, Flore, Undated. (Box-folder 81/19)
    - Tchernichova, Lubov, Signed, dated 1916.; Photographer: Jean de Strelecki. (Box-folder 81/20)
    - Tchernichova, Lubov, Undated. (Box-folder 81/21)
    - Bolm, Adolph and Karsavina, Thamar, In Schéhérazade.; Undated [ca. 1910]. (Box-folder 81/22)
    - Diaghilev, Serge and Cocteau, Jean, circa 1924, Photographer: Sasha (London). (Box-folder 81/22A)
    - Diaghilev, Serge and Massine, Léonide, Undated. (Box-folder 81/23)
    - Diaghilev, Serge and Nijinsky, Vaclav, Undated. (Box-folder 81/24)
    - Bolm, Adolph; Karsavina, Thamar; and Nijinsky, Vaclav, In Carnaval. Includes typed synopsis of the ballet.; Undated [ca. 1910]. (Box-folder 81/25)
    - Bakst, Léon: photograph of costume design for Firebird (unidentified dancer)., Includes typed synopsis of the ballet.; Undated [ca. 1910]. (Box-folder 81/26)
    - Bakst, Léon: photograph of set design for Schéhérazade (unidentified dancers) [two copies]., Includes typed synopsis of the ballet.; Undated [ca. 1910]. (Box-folder 81/27)
  - E. Miscellaneous (Box 81)
    - Souvenir book: The Art of Anna Pavlowa. (English) [No publication data; copyrighted 1914 by Max Rabinoff]; 16 p. (Box-folder 81/28)
    - Souvenir book: The Real Ballet Russe. (English) New York: Metropolitan Ballet Company, Inc., 1915; 24 p. [Contains photographic reproductions and color illustrations of Léon Bakst’s costume and set designs.] (Box-folder 81/29)
    - Souvenir book: Serge de Diaghileff’s Ballet Russe. (English) New York: Metropolitan Ballet Company, Inc., 1916; 40 p. [Contains photographic reproductions and color illustrations of Léon Bakst’s costume and set designs, as well as synopses of ballets performed by the company.] (Box-folder 81/30)
    - Program from Ballet Russes performances. May 1917, Paris. (French) [No publication data], 59 p. [Purchased 1989; acquisition information laid in.] (Box-folder 81/31)
    - Program notes from the première performance by the Ballets Russes of G. Rossini's La Boutique fantasque, arranged by O. Respighi and choreographed by L. Massine, London, 1919 Jun 5. (English) [No publication data], 6 p. (Box-folder 81/32)
    - Souvenir book: Soirèe [sic] de Gala in Honour of Her Majesty the Queen of Roumania. (English) New York: Metropolitan Opera House, 1916; 40 p. [Contains photographic reproductions and color illustrations of Léon Bakst’s costume and set designs, as well as synopses of ballets performed by the company.] (Box-folder 81/33)
    - Souvenir book: S. Hurok presents Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo [...] Season 1939-1940. (English) [No publication data]; 67 p. [Contains inscriptions (to “Jules”) from each company member, including those from Léonide Massine and Sol Hurok; several photographic reproductions of company members, color illustrations of costume and set designs by Picasso, Tchelitcheff, Dalí, etc.] (Box-folder 81/34)
    - Catalogo delle opere teatrali complete, novembre 1922. (Italian) [Milano]: Edizioni Ricordi, [1922]; 8 p. (Box-folder 81/35)